

Michael Ziegler

Mikeziegler123.github.io



4839 43rd Avenue Kenosha, WI 53144



Mobile(US): +1(815) 321-2752



Mikeziegler123@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

As a motivated leader, innovation & technology professional, software developer, and college graduate in 2019, I am excited to be at the deployment phase of a new career. I have held responsible roles in a variety of professional fields, and my unique variety of industry often leads me toward creative solutions to complex development problems.

- ★ Graduated from Middle Tennessee State University on May 4th, 2019.
- ★ Studied Law and Computer Science.
- **★** Natural problem solver with strong analytical and interpersonal skills.
- ★ 4+ years programming/development skills.

Knowledgeable & Pursuant in Learning: AWS, Best programming practices, effective practical algorithms, hands-on data structure(s) application, scalability, embedded systems, and linear regression.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

[Visual Studio 2019, Codeblocks, CodeLite]

★ OBJ-C [LeetCode, Visual Studio 2019] **★** JAVA [Dr. Java, Eclipse Studio, "JavaFX"]

SQL [M-SQLExpress, SQL Management Studio 18]

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The City Of Lake Forest, — IT Internship Lake Forest, IL | Innovation & Technology Division

January 2020 - PRESENT Phone: (847) 810-3591

- Perform technical maintenance on hardware and software for all city municipalities ranging from police vehicle radio communications, to data center server/switch repair/replacement/installation.
- Serve as one of 4 IT Professionals providing help-desk Support via remote connection, phone, email, Windows Powershell, network administrator software, and on-premise maintenance services, for 14 buildings using over 70 software systems citywide.

Rogers Enterprise, Inc. — Certified Consultant Racine, WI | Regency Mall

August 2019 - January 2020 Phone: (262) 598-0500

- Recruited, interviewed and trained new staff during management transition.
- Designed and implemented freelance IT solutions to resolve technical challenges during OS transition.

EDUCATION

Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro TN B.S. Pre-Law Cognate/Computer Science | GPA: 3.0 August 2016 - May 4th, 2019 | Full Time / Transfered Credits

EDUCATIONAL INTERNSHIPS | CONTRIBUTIONS

Pre-Law Internship: Judge McFarlin | Tidwell Murfreesboro, TN | City Courthouse | Judges Office

- Positioned for legal experience, remembered for technological help and knowledge.
- Offered to run the social media campaign for Judge Tidwell's next election cycle.

Pre-Law Internship: Senator Pamela J Althoff Crystal Lake, IL | Senator's Office

- Constituent Data entry during an active election cycle; Parade Planning.

Curriculum & Academic Policy Council Member Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Student Representative
- Nominated Board position

McHenry County College Student Senator Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Active within student government: 2009-2013
- Student body elected position

PROIECTS

aws Cloud Practitioner Certification

- Anticipated Certification Date: 03/22/2020
- Study Material: Udemy.com

Smart Home Synergy — *Startup*

Developed compatibility matrix for smart home devices similar to model used by 'PCPartsPicker.com'.





CV: Updated: 03/17/2020

Employment History:

The City Of Lake Forest Department of Innovation & Technology - Intern 2020-Current

• Perform technical maintenance on hardware and software for all city municipalities ranging from police vehicle radio communications, to data center server/switch repair/replacement/installation.

- Design & debug SQL queries to develop custom report solutions to simplify our analysis in situations including: new hardware roll-outs & cascading old hardware, software license inventory, etc.
- Administer user moves, adds, and changes in the city's active directory environment and associated systems.
- Administered help-desk Support via remote connection, phone, email, silently using Powershell & Network administrator Services, and on-premise maintenance services, for 13 city buildings using over 70 software systems.
- I work with a truly great team of only 4(including myself) individuals running around solving all of the city's technology problems, as well as meeting every week to discuss what we can do to push the city further forward with technology.

Rogers Enterprise, Inc. Certified Diamond Consultant 2019 - 2020

.....

- Personally recruited by an old coworker (now manager) from a previous jewelry store.
- Assumed the role of assistant manager, during manager transition.
- Worked with new manager making recommendations on hiring great staff, interviews, & many other major changes to the store's operations.
- Personally sold over \$38,000 in the month of December, exceeding my Platinum(highest tier) goal.
- Designed and implemented freelance IT solutions that automated repetitive computer processes & resolved other day-to-day technical challenges.

Specialized Pools Owner 2016-2019

- Started this business while finishing my degree in Tennessee. Specialized Pools flourished enough to supersede my banking position, and still runs today under management of my younger brother, who is now also finishing his degree in computer science at the same school.
- Above ground swimming pool services: Pool Openings, Pool Closings, Water Chemistry, Liner Replacements, Repairs & Maintenance, and Pool Builds.
- Performed all web marketing & website design for the business.
- Set up meetings with local pool supply distributors, to gain their customers in case they require great services.
- Master of my trade / Extensive knowledge of tools and methods.
- Received training from engineers and skilled individuals.
- Supervised hired, and trained employees.

US Bank Peak-Time Teller 2016-2017

- Consulted with customers and provided account services including:
- Receiving deposits
- Loan payments
- Cashing checks
- Issuing savings bonds
- Withdrawals
- Exceptional bookkeeping

- Issuing cashier's checks
- Traveler's checks
- series E bonds
- Independently preserved the location's customer service scores during a downturn.
- Answered any questions regarding our compliance with established federal regulations and protocols, and happily discussed any additional banking services we offered.

Erica's Fine Jewelry (Kenosha, WI) 2015-2016

- Accountable for store Sales day to day, building very Strong Customer Relationships
- Responsible for handling Routine Financial Transactions.
- Responsible for accepting and verifying large customer Payments, Deposits, and Credit Payments.
- Shipping and receiving both customer and vendor shipments, distributing, organizing, and stocking through stores.
- Educating each customer on the vast amount of options they have in the jewelry industry, from extensive diamond and gemstone education using tools from our diamond laboratory to drawing, customizing, and creating a custom piece.

.....

Kay Jewelers Assistant Manager - Woodfield Mall 2012-2015

- Assured that my team and I achieve our standards to reach our goals.
- Calculate, post, review, and discuss sales goals daily for the store, every employee, including myself.
- Responsible for opening and closing the store(s), and on call for responding and securing the store in the event the security alarm is tripped.
- Exceeded goals include: Sales, repair dollars, credit applications, extended service plans, and add on items.
- Personally sold over 220,000 in 2012-2013. My team and I had sold over 1.4 million.
- Conducted store meetings and disciplinary actions when needed.

Transfer/receive shipments, check in merchandise.

• Balance all registers each night.

Commission based sales environment.

- Management Training System certification completed
- Certified as a Diamontologist through Diamond Council of America.

Mchenry County College Student Orientation Leader - Crystal Lake, IL 2011-2012

- Run Summer Orientations for new student and parents at MCC
- New program, Developing Ideas to make it successful.
- Office Work: Sending mailers, phone assistance, organizing all paperwork into files.

Education:

Middle Tennessee State University (Current)

• B.S. Pre-Law/Computer Science 2019.

College of Lake County

- Acquired further credits toward my Bachelors program
- Mchenry County College
- Acquired credits equivalent to my Associate degree in science 2013 Johnsburg High School
 - Graduated from Johnsburg High School in 2009.

Internships:

Competitive/Paid IT Internship: IT Director-Jim Shaw, Assistant IT Director-Joe Gabanski

Lake Forest, IL | The City of Lake Forest | Department of Innovation & Technology

Pre-Law Internship: Judge McFarlin | Tidwell

Murfreesboro, TN | City Courthouse | Judges Office

Pre-Law Internship: Senator Pamela J Althoff

Crystal Lake, IL | Senator's Office

Curriculum & Academic Policy Council Member

Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

McHenry County College Student Senator

Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

Contributions & Affiliations:

- MCC Curriculum and Academic Policy Representative Nominated 2011
- Appointed Student Senator on Executive board, MCC 2010
- Appointed McHenry County College's Board of conduct Student representative
- MCC L.E.A.D member 2009-2011
- Representative for MCC, Springfield, IL Lobby day
- Door to door sales associate for subcontractor of Comcast selling Xfinity package
- DCA certified Diamontologist via The Diamond Council of America
- Certified in Kay Jeweler's management training program
- Wilmot mountain Ski instructor.
- Played Bass/Guitar in 3 performing bands, one of which toured to Nashville, TN.
- Student Orientation Leader. Mchenry County College